

+91 9325438482

- patilyogesh2247@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/ in/yogesh-patilb222a2a9/
- Pune

SKILLS

Technologies

GCP	Spark	Scala	Hadoop
PySpark	Dataproc	SQL	Big Query
Dataflow	Terraform	Hive	Gradle

Tools / Methodologies

Airflow	Control-M	Eclipse	Agile
Jenkins	GithubActions	JIRA	Intellij

ACHIEVEMENTS



Excellence in Delivering Critical Solutions

Recognized for implementing and delivering critical solutions and successful collaboration with many stake holder.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Engineering

North Maharashtra University

2011-2014

65%

Diploma in Computer Engg.

MSBTE, Mumbai

2008-2011 64.69%

LANGUAGES

English Proficient ••••

German Basic Al •

YOGESH PATIL

Cloud Data Engineer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over 8+ years of extensive experience as Software developer. Around 4 years of experience in Big Data technologies implementing end-to-end solutions using Scala/Java/Python.

2+ years of Experience in Google Cloud Platform.

Throughout in IT carrier, learned new skills and worked on different technologies comprehensively.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Publicis Sapient

Aug 2023- Present

Pune

Cloud Data Engineer

- Expertise includes successfully migrating on-premises ETL workflows to GCP, optimizing processes for enhanced scalability and performance.
- Additionally, Responsible for analyzing Informatica jobs and MSSQL queries, translating this insight into the creation of effective data pipelines on GCP.
- Actively involved in working with GCP Dataflow, BigQuery's utilizing its powerful capabilities to process and transform large-scale data sets efficiently.
- Orchestrated and automate complex workflows using Cloud Composer

Deutsche Bank

Jan 2019- July 2023

Pune

Big Data/Cloud Engineer

- Experience in working with GCP Dataproc, BigQuery, and Cloud Composer reflecting a deep understanding of cloud-based data processing and analytics.
- Conducted detailed analysis aligned with business needs and translated requirements into code implementation using Spark, Scala, and Play Framework.
- In the realm of Cloud migration, actively engaged with various components including Terraform, Dataporc, BigQuery, GKE, Airflow, Cloud Functions, etc.
- Architected a reconciliation framework employing Java, Spark, and Spring.

Bitwise Solution

Apr 2015- Sep 2018

Pune

Programmer Analyst

- Demonstrates extensive familiarity with the entire Software Development Life Cycle and showcases exceptional programming and debugging skills in Java
- Engaged in comprehensive coding using Java, J2EE, and Web Services for end-toend application development, employing IDEs such as Eclipse, STS, and RAD.
- Responsible for crafting and modifying pySpark applications to align with specific business requirements.
- Contributed to the development of MapReduce applications using Java, and Hive

CERTIFICATION

Associate Cloud Engineer

Jan-2024

GCP Data Engineer

In Progress

Certificate of Training - Big Data Engineer

ETL Hive

04/2018 - 08/2018